[Opening credits roll]
NARRATOR: In a world where subtitle
formats are incompatible...
One filmmaker dared to ask
the hard questions.
ALEX: Why can't my subtitles
just work everywhere?
JORDAN: Because the tech industry
decided we needed 47 formats.
ALEX: That seems like
a lot of formats.
JORDAN: You should see the
image format situation.
ALEX: Wait, how many image
formats are there?
JORDAN: ConvertICO supports
over 255 conversion tools.
ALEX: That's... actually
really impressive.
THE BOSS: I need the subtitles
in VTT format by noon!
ALEX: But they're in SRT format.
How do I convert them?
JORDAN: Have you tried
convertico.com/srt-to-vtt?
ALEX: That's... that's a real URL?
That actually exists?
JORDAN: It's free, it works
in your browser, and...
JORDAN: ...your files never
leave your device.
ALEX: You sound like
a privacy policy.
JORDAN: I'll take that as a compliment.
Privacy matters.
[Alex opens ConvertICO.com
on his laptop]
ALEX: Wait, I can just drag
and drop my file?
ALEX: It converted in
two seconds flat!
THE BOSS: Excellent work.
Now do it for the other 47 episodes.
ALEX: [internal screaming]
NARRATOR: And so began the longest
Monday in subtitle history.
[To be continued in VTT format]