hello everyone have you ever thought
about the speed of your internet
connection well chances are yes you have
because when you were shopping for
high-speed broadband internet for your
home or business one of the first things
you thought about was speed such as
upload and download speeds and as you
were shopping you may have seen internet
service providers advertising broadband
internet speeds of 100 megabits per
second 500 megabits per second or 1,000
megabits per second well these speeds
that are advertised are technically not
the speed at which data travels over a
network but it's actually a measurement
of the maximum amount of data that's
transferred over a network and this is
what's known as bandwidth bandwidth is
measured in bits per second or BPS in
other words it's a measurement of how
much data is transferred over a network
in 1 second so for example if you have a
100 megabit internet service connection
then that means that a maximum of 100
megabits of data can be transferred in 1
second or if you have a 500 megabit
connection then that means that a
maximum of 500 megabits of data can be
transferred in 1 second so even though
the 100 and 500 megabit connection
transmit data at the same speed the 500
megabit connection will seem like it's
faster because it can transfer five
times times more data in 1 second than
the 100 megabit connection so this is
why internet service providers advertise
their internet connections as
speeds so as an analogy we can use an
illustration of water flowing through a
pipe and depending upon the diameter of
the pipe it will directly affect how
much water can flow through it so the
smaller diameter pipe will represent a
lower bandwidth connection and the
larger diameter pipe will represent a
higher bandwidth connection so as you
can see the flow of water is traveling
at the same rate in both pipes but since
the bottom pipe is wider than the top
one it's able to flow a lot more water
at the same time more than a smaller
pipe which can fill up the container at
the other end a lot
faster hey guys before I continue I just
want to thank my sponsor for this video
which is brilliant and Brilliant is
simply brilliant brilliant is an online
learning center where you can learn and
improve your skills in as little as 15
minutes per day but what makes brilliant
different is that they don't just teach
you by giving you a lecture but instead
they teach you by using interactive
exercises that you participate in which
helps in reinforcing learning with
guided bite-sized lessons brilliant
makes it easy to stay on track see your
progress and build your own
problemsolving skills one concept at a
time and with thousands of lessons
available you can be assured that you'll
find something that you're interested in
learning about and right now you can try
everything that brilliant has to offer
for free for a full 30 Days by going to
brilliant.org
slower or click the link in the
description or scan the QR code on the
screen and you also get 20% off an
annual premium
subscription so this works just like an
internet connection if both both of
these connections were to download a
video from the internet that's 4 GB in
size the 500 megabit connection can
download the video to your computer a
lot faster so in theory the 100 megabit
connection would take about 5 1 12
minutes to download a 4 GB video while
the 500 megabit connection would only
take a little over a minute or if some
of you were old enough to remember this
if you were us if you were using an AOL
dialup connection back in the 1990s
using a whopping 56k BPS connection
using your phone line it would take you
about a week to download a 4 gigabyte
video now this is providing that AOL
doesn't randomly kick you off your
connection and no one in your home wants
to use your phone because this will
cause you to disconnect and then you'll
have to reconnect and you'll have to
restart the download all over again from
scratch so again these calculations are
just on paper because in the real world
there's internet traffic lag and
equipment that would affect the actual
time it takes to download but needless
to say the more bandwidth you have the
faster and smoother your internet
experience will be but also the higher
the bandwidth the higher price you'll
have to pay your internet service
provider now keep in mind bandwidth is
measured in both download and upload
speeds but when isps are advertising
their internet speeds such as 100 or 500
megabits per second they are referring
to the download speed and typically the
upload speed would be only a fraction of
the download speed so for example if an
ISP is advertising a download speed of
100 megabits per second the upload speed
may be around 10 megabits per second now
the reason for this is because the
download speed is what's most important
when regular consumers are doing normal
things such as browsing websites
watching videos writing emails and so on
so having a high upload speed is not
really important but if the consumer is
running a business and they are
uploading large files on a regular basis
or if they are a live streamer for
example on YouTube well then having a
faster upload speed would be needed so
guys I want to thank you for watching
this video on bandwidth Please Subscribe
and I will see you in the next video